In this video, I will introduce the actual hair growth function.
In the previous version, users can only check the hair growth effect through Vray rendering.
Since the 2025.0 version, the material type in the shell has increased to a new material hair growth rate.
Users can directly create and check the hair growth effect in the 3D window without rendering,
thereby greatly simplifying the workflow.
In addition, the hair that is based on Vray rendering can only be checked in the rendering window,
limiting its use in the external application program.
In comparison, the hair growth rate material can lead to USD format,
greatly increasing the compatibility with external tools.
Currently, this function can only be used in Windows systems, and will also support Mac systems in the future.
Let's take a look at how to set the hair growth rate.
If you want to display or hide hair growth rate material in the 3D window,
you can put the mouse on the clothing rendering option in the switch menu,
click the icon to display the hair growth rate,
and then use the function.
At this time, the hair growth rate material will be displayed on the fabric of the hair growth rate.
You can check it in the 3D window in time.
You can also click on the color of the hair growth rate randomly,
and assign random colors to each hair growth rate,
so that it is easier to check the various shapes of hair growth rates.
When you use a fabric with hair growth rate material,
these options will be banned and cannot be selected.
You can control the hair growth rate in the 3D window by choosing three different options.
Let's go to the main menu, open the settings,
then open the user's definition, and click the 3D option.
In the hair growth rate form, you can see three options,
the original hair, the plane, and the limit.
Click each option to display the difference in the 3D window.
Selecting the original hair will display the original hair with thickness and width,
which helps to check the overall structure of the hair.
Selecting the plane will display the hair with thickness but no thickness,
and the hair with thickness and width will display the hair with width but no thickness.
The selected option is default.
The limit shows that the hair is a simple curve,
without thickness or width.
We can select the original,
and get a more realistic appearance of the hair.
Now let's see how to directly apply the hair growth rate material to the costume.
Click the Fabric 1 in the object window.
In the attribute editor,
change the type of material to hair growth rate.
Use the Fabric 1 fabric for the costume.
It will immediately display the hair in the 3D window.
You can also select various hair types from the following hair types.
At the bottom of the attribute editor,
just like the previous hair dye type,
you can adjust the details of the attribute,
such as parameters,
shape settings,
and default application to set the hair style.
Here we will quickly adjust some of the parameter values,
to show the work principle of hair setting.
Although the hair rate and hair are only dyed,
use the same parameters,
and set the attribute.
But in the hair dye window,
the distribution of these two hair types is different.
In the hair dye list,
a new random option has been added.
By adjusting the seed distribution value,
even if you use the same parameters,
you can also create a slightly different hair arrangement.
After setting the parameters of the hair,
now let's open the synchronized dyeing in the hair dye window,
to see the final dyeing effect of the hair.
You can also export the hair dye data created in the hole
as a usd file and use it in other software.
Come to the main menu,
click on the file export,
select the usd format,
confirm the storage path,
enter the file name,
click on the save,
and then click on the export usd window.
Ensure that the selection contains the hair dye data option,
so that the hair dye data is exported to the usd file.
Here we show a section of the hair dye,
in the virtual engine,
used to simulate a short video.
In the 2025 version,
the new hair dyeing material can be used to create the same hair dye
as the 3D window and the dyeing window.
In addition,
by exporting the hair dye data,
you can also import it into other tools,
and use it in various creative projects.